Finding Aid for John B. Trevor, Jr. Papers 1939-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John B. Trevor, Jr. Papers 1939-1987
Trevor, John B., 1909-
John B. Trevor was active in various local (New York state) and national conservative and patriotic organizations; topical files, 1930s-1970s, contain correspondence, published materials, clippings, and ephemera detailing his interest in, and involvement with, such organizations as the Sons of the American Revolution and the American Coalition of Patriotic Societies.
0125 Aa 2
14 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The Trevor papers were given to Dr. John Tanton (Donor no. 7087 ) who donated them to the library in August 2000. Additional materials were received in 2010.
The collection is open for research.
John B. Trevor, Jr. was involved in a variety of immigration reform and patriotic organizations. He was, for example, a member of the advisory board of the Cooper-Hewitt Museum of Design, treasurer of the Empire State Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, treasurer of the Committee of Episcopal Laymen of New York, treasurer of the Pioneer Fund, as well as being active in the American Coalition of Patriotic Societies.
The papers of John B. Trevor, Jr. consist of correspondence and collected materials relating to his activities with various patriotic organizations, including the American Coalition, the Sons of the American Revolution, and the Pioneer Fund.
Subjects:
Trevor, John B., 1909-; American Coalition of Patriotic, Civic, and Fraternal Societies.; Patriotic societies--New York (State); Pioneer Fund.; Sons of the American Revolution. Empire State Society.; Weyher, Harry Frederick, 1921-
- Topical File 1930s-1960s
  - Alexander, Mrs. Anne (Church Layman's Association) (Box 1)
  - Alliance, Inc (Box 1)
  - Allied Patriotic Societies (Box 1)
  - America's Future-John T. Flynn (Box 1)
  - American Defense Society (Box 1)
  - Alvins, Alfred (National Labor Relations Board) (Box 1)
  - American Federation of Labor (Box 1)
  - American Literature Contest (Box 1)
  - Arens, Richard (staff director, House Un-American Activities Committee) (Box 1)
  - B (Box 1)
  - Barrow, Byron (Box 1)
  - Bettelheim, Col. E.S., Jr. (Military Order of the World Wars (Box 1)
  - Braun, Rev. Leopold L.S. (Assumptionist) (Box 1)
  - Bricker Amendment (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Donald B. (Scotland) (Box 1)
  - Burke, John (Box 1)
  - Child Labor (Box 1)
  - Children Of The American Revolution (Box 1)
  - Circuit Riders, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Colonial Wars, Society of (Box 1)
  - Committee of Episcopal Laymen of New York, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Communism, Information about (Box 1)
  - Cooper-Hewitt Museum of Design (Box 1)
    (Trevor was member of advisory board)
  - Constitution Party (Box 1)
  - Counterattack (Box 1)
  - Donner, Robert (Box 1)
  - Col. Wickliffe P. Draper (Box 1)
  - Dies, Congressman Martin (Box 1)
  - Dunn, Rogers (Box 1)
  - Education (Box 1)
  - Entente Internationale Anticommuniste (E.I.A.) (Box 1)
  - Erb, Mrs. Ray L. (Box 2)
  - European War (Box 2)
  - Eugenics (Box 2)
  - Federation For Constitutional Government (Box 2)
  - Foreign Trade (Box 2)
  - Foundation For Economic Education, Inc. (Box 2)
  - Frazier, Hon. Lynn J. (Box 2)
  - Goethe, C.M. 1958-1966, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Gwinn, Hon. Ralph W. (Box 2)
  - H (Box 2)
  - Hart, Merwin K. (National Economic Council) (Box 2)
  - Hawaiian Statehood (Box 2)
  - Hichborn, Franklin (Box 2)
  - Holden, Edward (Box 2)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar (Box 2)
  - Ingram, Rev. T. Robert (St. Thomas Episcopal Church, Houston, TX) (Box 2)
  - Isaacs, Stanley M. (New York City councilman) (Box 2)
  - Japanese Aggression (Box 2)
  - Krop, Dr. F.J. (Entente Fraternelle Internationale) (Box 2)
  - League For Industrial Democracy (Box 2)
  - Lectures (Box 2)
  - Leetch, Mrs. W.D. (American Coalition of Patriotic Societies) 1956-1964, 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Lend Lease Bill (Box 3)
  - Lipscomb, Mrs. Peggy R. (American Coalition of Patriotic Societies) (Box 3)
  - Long, Hamilton A. (Box 3)
  - Lory, Milton M. 1957-1964 (American Coalition of Patriotic Societies), 4 folders (Box 3)
  - McCarran, Hon. Pat (Box 3)
  - MacLean, Bunny (Box 3)
  - Masons (Box 3)
  - Matthews, J.R. (Box 3)
  - McCarthy, Hon. Joseph (Box 3)
  - McClive, Isabel, (1967 deceased) (Box 3)
  - Moseley, Gen. George Van Horn (Box 3)
  - National Federation Of Christian Laymen (Box 3)
  - National Putnam Letters Committee (Box 3)
    (see also Putnam, Carleton)
  - National Renaissance Party (Box 4)
  - National Republic (Box 4)
  - New Deal (Box 4)
  - New York State Economic Council (Box 4)
  - Newspaper Contacts (Box 4)
  - Patriotic Activities (Box 4)
  - Peoples League Against Communism and War (Box 4)
  - Poland (Box 4)
  - Post, Mrs. Gladys E. (American Coalition of Patriotic Societies) (Box 4)
  - Pro-America (Box 4)
  - Putnam, Carleton (Box 4)
    (see also National Putnam Letters Committee)
  - Pyramid Prophecy (Box 4)
  - Rudd, Col. Augustin G. (NY Sons of the American Revolution) (Box 4)
  - Social (Box 4)
  - Societies (Box 4)
  - SAR (Box 4)
  - Sons of the American Revolution
    - 1939-1941 (Box 4)
    - National Society General 1957-1966, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Empire State Society 1957-1966, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Empire State Society, John B. Trevor, Jr. (treasurer) file April 25, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Schools-Subversive Activities (Box 4)
  - Servicio Autimarxista (Box 4)
  - Smoot, Dan (Box 4)
  - Spain (Box 4)
  - Steele, Walter (National Republic) (Box 5)
  - Supreme Court (Box 5)
  - Swan, Donald A. (Association for the Preservation of Freedom of Choice) (Box 5)
  - Taft, Sen. Robert (Box 5)
  - Ten Million Americans (Box 5)
  - Trevor, John B., Jr
    - Speech, "The Tennessee Valley-An Experiment in Collectivism" 1938 (Box 5)
    - Speech, "Should America Enter the European War?" October 23, 1941 (Box 5)
  - Walker, Mrs. Flora (Box 5)
  - War (Box 5)
  - War Committees (Box 5)
  - Weyher, Harry F. 1957-1966 (New York attorney), 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Winchester, James (author) (Box 5)
- Topical File 1960s-1970s
  - A-Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Air Force Manual (Box 6)
  - Alexander, Robert C. (Box 6)
  - Alford, Dale (Box 6)
  - American-Asian Educational Exchange (Box 6)
  - American Conservative Union (Box 6)
  - American Friends of Antibolshevic Bloc of Nations Inc. (Box 6)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Box 6)
  - American Immigration & Citizenship Conference (Box 6)
  - Americans for Constitutional Action (Box 6)
  - Americans for National Security (Box 6)
  - Americans for Patriotism, Inc. (Box 6)
  - American Legion (Box 6)
  - American Nazi Party-Rockwell (Box 6)
  - American-Southern African Council (Box 6)
  - Andersonville (Box 6)
  - Anti-Communist Liaison, Inc. "Tactics" (Box 6)
  - Anti-Defamation League (Box 6)
  - Aware, Inc. (Box 6)
  - Author's Fund, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - B-Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Barker, C. Austin (Box 6)
    (Order of Patriots & Founders; lawyer with firm of Hornblower-Weeks-Hemphill Noyes)
  - Bibliography (Box 6)
  - Birch (John Birch Society) (Box 6)
  - Birth Control (Box 6)
  - Braden, Spruille (Box 6)
  - Budget-Federal (Box 6)
  - Bunch, Dr. Ralph (Box 6)
  - Butterfield, Alice D. (American Coalition of Patriotic Societies) (Box 6)
  - C-Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Catholic Freedom Foundation (Box 6)
  - Children of the American Revolution-NY Chapter (Box 6)
  - China (Box 7)
  - Christian Nationalist Crusade (Box 7)
    (see also Gerald L.K. Smith)
  - Church (Box 7)
  - Church League of America (Box 7)
  - C.I.A. (Central Intelligence Agency) (Box 7)
  - Cincinnati, Society of the (Box 7)
  - Citizen's Council Forum (Box 7)
  - Committee of One Million (Box 7)
  - Congress (Box 7)
  - Connally Amendment (retention of) (Box 7)
  - Conservative Party (Box 7)
  - Constitution, U.S. (Box 7)
  - Constitutional Amendments (Box 7)
  - Cooper Hewitt Museum of Design-Bank Statements-"Committee to Save" 05/06/1969 (Box 7)
  - Cooper Hewitt Museum of Design (Box 7)
  - Cuba (Box 7)
  - D-Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Dahlke, Clarence (Box 7)
  - Daughters of the American Rev (Box 7)
  - Defenders of the American Constitution, Inc (Box 7)
  - Disarmament (Box 7)
  - Drugs (Box 7)
  - DuBerrier, Hilaire Reports (Box 7)
  - E-Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Education (Box 7)
  - Eugenics (Box 7)
  - Extremist Group (Box 7)
  - F-Miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Feighan, Hon. Michael A. (Box 8)
  - Flag (Box 8)
  - Flag Foundation 1975 (Box 8)
  - Fluoridation (Box 8)
  - For America-Bonner Fellers (Box 8)
  - Foreign Intelligence Digest (Box 8)
  - Foreign Policy (Box 8)
  - G-Miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Garrett, Dr. Henry E. (Charlottesville Educational Foundation) (Box 8)
  - General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (Box 8)
  - George, Dr. W.C. (Box 8)
  - Gerard, Col. James W. II (Box 8)
  - Gold (Box 8)
  - Goldwater, Senator Barry (Box 8)
  - Goodwin, Fred (Box 8)
  - Grant, Gen. Ulysses S. III (Ret.) (Box 8)
  - Group Research (Box 8)
  - H-Miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Hargis, Dr. Billy James (Christian Crusade) (Box 8)
  - Hate Mongers (Box 8)
  - Harriss, Robert M. (Box 8)
  - Hawkes, A.W (Box 8)
  - Human Events (Box 8)
  - Humane slaughter, etc. (Box 8)
  - Hungary (Box 8)
  - Immigration-Map of Radical Meeting Places (Box 8)
  - Income Tax (Box 8)
  - Integration (Box 9)
  - Institutes for the Achievement of Human Potential (Box 9)
  - International Association for Advancements of Ethnology and Eugenics, Inc. (A. O'Keefe) (Box 9)
  - International Services of Information, Foundation, Inc. (INFORM) (Box 9)
  - J-Miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. (Box 9)
  - K-Miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - Kennedy, John F. (Box 9)
  - L-Miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - Lee, J. Bracken (Box 9)
  - Lemons, J. Stanley (Associate Professor of History, Rhode Island College) (Box 9)
  - Lindsay, John V., M.C. (Box 9)
  - Mc-Miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - M-Miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - MacArthur, General Douglas (Box 9)
  - Maguire, Russell (Box 9)
  - Malone, Hon. Geo. W. (Box 9)
  - Manion, Dean Clarence Manion Forum (Box 9)
  - Mankind Quarterly
    - Committee work (Box 9)
    - Col. Gayre & Trudeau Institute Banner, Seal, Insignia, Etc. (Box 9)
    - Gayre Dinner October 14, 1965 (Box 9)
    - Lt. Col. Gayre 1960-1966 (Box 9)
  - Mason, Frank E. (Box 9)
  - Mason, Frank E (Box 10)
  - Mental Health (Box 10)
  - Michaelson, Charles S. (Box 10)
  - Milbank, Jeremiah Jr. (Box 10)
  - Minute Women (Box 10)
  - Montgomery, George S. Jr. (Box 10)
  - Moore Hugh Fund (Box 10)
  - Moral Rearmament (Box 10)
  - Morris, Hon. Robert (Box 10)
  - Murray, James G. (Box 10)
  - N-Miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - National Committee for Economic Freedom (Box 10)
  - National Defense (Box 10)
  - National Economic Council, Inc. (Mark M. Jones) (Box 10)
  - National Review (Box 10)
  - National Strategy Information Center, Inc. (Frank Barnett) (Box 10)
  - National War Vets (Box 10)
  - Negro, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - New England Women (Box 10)
  - New Yorkers for Richard M. Nixon (Box 11)
  - Norman, Dr. Herbert, Case (Box 11)
  - O-Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) (Box 11)
  - Oppenheimer, J. R. (Box 11)
  - P-Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - Pittman, R. Carter (Box 11)
  - Political Program (Box 11)
  - Population Crisis Committee (Box 11)
  - Public Action Inc (Box 11)
  - The Puritan Foundation, Inc. (Box 11)
  - Putnam, Carleton (Box 11)
  - Q-Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - Queen Boys (Box 11)
  - R-Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - Regnery (Henry Regnery Co.) (Box 11)
  - Religion (Box 11)
  - Republican Party (Box 11)
  - Rich, Col. William L. (Box 11)
  - Roosevelt, Archibald (Box 11)
  - S-Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - Satterfield, John C. (Box 11)
  - Schafly (Phyllis) for Congress (Box 11)
  - Segregation (Box 11)
  - Senate Internal Security, sub-committee (Box 11)
  - Shuey, Dr. Audrey (Box 11)
  - Smith, Gerald L.K. (Box 11)
    (see also Christian Nationalist Crusade)
  - Sons of the American Revolution
    - Committee Correspondence 1964-1967 (Box 11)
    - New York Chapter 1972-1979 (Box 11)
  - South Africa-"Summary Scope" (Box 11)
  - Speeches (Box 11)
  - Status of Forces Treaty (Box 11)
  - State Department (Box 11)
  - Stephenson, Rear Admiral C.S. (Box 11)
  - Stone, Willis E. (Box 11)
  - Subversives, Organizations, Etc. (Box 12)
  - Supreme Court (Box 12)
  - T-Miscellaneous (Box 12)
  - Taxation (Box 12)
  - Tourism U.S.A. (Box 12)
  - Trade Policy Committee (Box 12)
  - Trevor, J.B., Jr. (Box 12)
    (Background material for Speech "Perspectives for Patriots-'74' ")
  - John B. Trevor, Jr. (American Coalition File) (Box 12)
  - Tshombe Emergency Committee (Box 12)
  - U-Miscellaneous (Box 12)
  - Un-American Activities, House Committee on (Box 12)
  - United Nations (Box 12)
  - United World Federalists, Inc. (Box 12)
  - V-Miscellaneous (Box 12)
  - W-Miscellaneous (Box 12)
  - Walker, Mrs. Flora A., Pension Payment (Box 12)
  - Walker, Mrs. Wm. S. (Box 12)
  - Walker, Major General Edwin A. (Box 12)
  - Walter, Hon. Francis E. (Box 12)
  - Ward, Henry Dec (Box 12)
  - Warner, Col. Wm. E. (Box 12)
  - Watson, Theo S. (Box 12)
  - Willoughby-Maj. Gen. C.A. (Box 12)
  - Winston, Robert A. (News for Action, Col. Fox) (Box 12)
  - XYZ-Miscellaneous (Box 12)
  - Young Americans For Freedom, Inc. (Box 12)
- Pioneer Fund Correspondence
  (Trevor was Treasurer of the organization)
  - Undated 1958-1981, 74 folders (Box 13)
  - 1982-1987, 59 folders (Box 14)